♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 12=
Xu Xian, just let me explain.
Qing, you've messed things up.
(Silk Shop)
Mr. Gu.
You're here.
I'm here for the fabrics.
What kind of material
are you looking for today?
Mr. Gu,
I want ten chi
of this bolt of red cloud brocade.
You've set your sights on this?
Any happy event coming?
It's still early,
but there are some signs.
I'm just planning ahead.
Mrs. Fang,
you and Constable Fang
have treated Xu Xian
like your own son all these years.
And your efforts have finally paid off.
Congratulations!
Miss Bai, you don't need
to wait by the door.
But I have to explain it to you.
Don't bother.
Do you misunderstand Qing?
I don't care about that.
But Qing really is just my bodyguard.
It's not what you think.
No need to explain.
You're nice, so it's only natural
some guys would like you.
Don't you think
Qing is exceptionally handsome?
I'm not interested in a man's looks.
But Qing is a girl.
Really?
I swear it's true.
Two girls traveling alone wasn't safe,
so she disguised herself as a man.
Qing.
We're going to be
best buddies
forever.
Well, it tastes good
when you eat
the chicken and fish together.
Especially the shrimp.
I have to grab one.
The chicken...
I just caught this
up in the hills today.
It is very fresh.
Try it.
It's good.
The meat is so tender
and well-flavored.
I heard from Aunt
that you love steamed bass.
I went to Cuiyu Pavilion
early this morning just to get this.
Try it.
Okay.
It looks like you two not only made up,
but also made great progress.
Stop that nonsense!
If you like it, then eat more.
Fine.
After all, this is the chicken
you caught up in the hills.
And this is the fish Miss Bai bought
early in the morning.
I owe you for this meal.
I'll be quiet.
Xu Xian,
I have an idea
for Aunt's birthday gift this year.
What is it?
Qing, why are you only
eating plain rice today?
Have some dishes, here.
This meat is delicious.
Eat up.
You should eat more.
Listen, your face is longer
than a willow branch by the lake.
Do you want a man too?
Want me to help you?
Shut it. Even a meal
can't keep your mouth shut.
Just eat.
Qing,
do you want to pick out
a birthday gift for Aunt with me?
Qing, you look beautiful.
Suits you, right?
You look so beautiful.
Suzhen, let's go.
(Silk Shop)
Suzhen.
You must be Qing.
Aunt.
Miss Qing is pretty and charming.
To be honest,
I had my suspicions all along.
You should dress like this from now on.
You look so pretty.
Thank you, Aunt.
Aunt, we were just afraid
of being bullied on the road.
With Xu Xian around,
you won't be afraid anymore.
Wait here. I want to show you something.
Look at this fabric.
The color is so vibrant,
and it's so soft to the touch.
Perfect for you.
You can use it to make jackets and bibs
for your child later on.
Aunt, aren't we here
to pick a birthday gift for you?
Why are you picking
something out for me?
It doesn't matter.
I've already celebrated
dozens of birthdays.
Let's not bother with this.
Seeing you happily together
is all I want.
That's the best gift I want.
Aunt.
What do you want to have first,
a boy or a girl?
I've even thought of a bunch of names.
For a boy, Xu Chengzhi.
For a girl, Xu Wanqing.
Do you like them?
Aunt.
Isn't that Xu Xian?
Aunt, you must be seeing things.
Xu Xian is at home
setting up for your birthday.
He couldn't be out here.
You must miss him so much.
You're seeing him in everyone.
Uncle.
The most handsome head disciple.
Greetings.
Greetings, Mr. Fang.
We meet again.
Everything is in here?
Wonderful.
If Wenhui sees this,
I can't even imagine
how happy she'll be.
Ever since your aunt married me,
she's been busy with the housework
and taking care of you.
I don't even know when
she just stopped having any time
to doll herself up.
Uncle.
Everything is fine now.
You're all grown up,
so your aunt will have plenty of time
to doll herself up.
Uncle, this is all my fault.
Xu Xian, you mustn't
believe what outsiders say.
Your aunt didn't want a child of her own
not just because of you.
It was a decision I made with your aunt.
It was our choice.
Your aunt
poured all her motherly love
into you.
You are our child.
I understand, Uncle.
Good. Let's have some tea.
(Longevity)
We'll have a big banquet tomorrow,
so let's have our own
family gathering today.
Come on, everyone sit down.
Try my cooking.
I made all of these.
My dear, I thought we agreed
to order dishes at Cuiyu Pavilion.
That's such a waste of money.
Well, let's just sit then. Sit.
Thank you for your hard work, my dear.
Take the seat of honor.
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪